<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BES QUANTITATIVE ECOLOGY GROUP on BES QUANTITATIVE ECOLOGY GROUP</title>
    <link>https://BES-QSIG.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BES QUANTITATIVE ECOLOGY GROUP on BES QUANTITATIVE ECOLOGY GROUP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the new Quantitative Ecology Site</title>
      <link>https://BES-QSIG.github.io/post/welcome-to-new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BES-QSIG.github.io/post/welcome-to-new-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have migrated from our old &lt;a href=&#34;https://besquantitativeecology.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wordpress site&lt;/a&gt; in order to keep everything in one place. Our Wordpress site will function as an archive, but new material will be updated here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our aim as a group is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support quantitative skills development for all ecologists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve dissemination of new quantitative methods to their users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a forum to advance quantitative ecology in its own right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ideas for events, workshops or courses that you would like to see us organise (or would like to organise yourself with our support), please &lt;a href=&#34;https://BES-QSIG.github.io/#contact&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Your R</title>
      <link>https://BES-QSIG.github.io/courses/advancingr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BES-QSIG.github.io/courses/advancingr/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-here&#34;&gt;Getting here&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course is taking place in the Waterhouse Room at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.liverpool.ac.uk/conferences-and-events/venue-finder/foresight-centre/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Foresight Centre&lt;/a&gt;, University of Liverpool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d1681.7435965583238!2d-2.9694946677972656!3d53.40866296464316!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x487b211782d9e8e3%3A0x8524f47e6bc7433d!2sForesight+Centre+(Block+J)%2C+Liverpool+L3+5QA!5e0!3m2!1sen!2suk!4v1543347942213&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;road&#34;&gt;Road&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the M62 (end of motorway 3 miles)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the M53( Wirral/Mersey Tunnels &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; mile)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use L3 5DA for sat nav&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rail&#34;&gt;Rail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liverpool Lime St Station is a 10 minute walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For local public transport please contact Merseytravel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;air&#34;&gt;Air&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liverpool John Lennon  Airport is 7 Miles away from the Foresight Centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Airlink 500 loops to the city centre every 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-course-instructions&#34;&gt;Pre-course Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below see instructions on the software and R packages to install &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; you arrive. Note that you will receive the greatest benefit of the course if you have already installed the software and packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing your R</title>
      <link>https://BES-QSIG.github.io/events/2018-12-3-advancing-your-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BES-QSIG.github.io/events/2018-12-3-advancing-your-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The British Ecological Society Quantitative Ecology Group are hosting a two-day R workshop which will cover reproducible data manipulation and visualisation workflows in R. Day One will be focussed on the tidyverse, while Day Two will move into working with spatial data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-one-data-manipulation-and-visualisation-in-r-using-the-tidyverse&#34;&gt;Day One: Data manipulation and visualisation in R using the tidyverse&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;workshop-leader-gergana-daskalova-university-of-edinburgh-coding-club&#34;&gt;Workshop leader: Gergana Daskalova, University of Edinburgh, Coding Club&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tidyverse collection of packages (tidyr, dplyr, ggplot2, broom and more) is a great tool for efficient data manipulation, visualisation and analysis. In this workshop, you’ll learn how to manipulate data using pipes, build functions and apply them in a pipe, summarise model output and visualise data analysis results. We’ll then delve into functional programming using purr. Along the way, we’ll be using large ecological datasets, so you will get hands-on experience with how you can tackle big data in ecology and achieve a lot in not that many lines of code. You’ll gain skills in customising different types of graphs to maximise the impact of your data visualisation and finally, we will be doing all of this under the Markdown framework for reproducible report to promote transparency in research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-two-spatial-data-manipulation-and-visualisation-in-r&#34;&gt;Day Two: Spatial data manipulation and visualisation in R&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;workshop-leader-reto-schmucki-centre-for-ecology-and-hydrology&#34;&gt;Workshop leader: Reto Schmucki, Centre for Ecology and Hydrology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geocomputing and manipulating geographic data are important skills for modelling spatial phenomena and have become increasingly important in data science. Over the last decade, there has been important progress in open-source GIS. In this workshop, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to create, import and manipulate spatial data, using the rich spatial ecosystem available in R (sf, sp, raster, tmap, leaflet). With emphasis on Simple Features for R available through the sf package. You will learn how to extract spatial information, merge complex data sets, visualise geographic data and produce interactive maps. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ll work on real-word data and explore how to harness the power of R and how it links to other open-source GIS solutions (QGIS, GRASS, PostGIS). At the end of this workshop, you will be able to implement a workflow to manipulate data, run analysis and visualise your results, using open-source solutions with a transparent and fully reproducible workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The option is available to come to both days, or just one of the two. Lunch and refreshments will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/advancing-your-r-tickets-49210051589&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SOLD OUT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
