<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on BES QUANTITATIVE ECOLOGY GROUP</title>
    <link>/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on BES QUANTITATIVE ECOLOGY GROUP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Your R</title>
      <link>/courses/advancingr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/advancingr/</guid>
      <description>Getting here The course is taking place in the Waterhouse Room at the Foresight Centre, University of Liverpool.
 Road From the M62 (end of motorway 3 miles)
From the M53( Wirral/Mersey Tunnels 3&amp;frasl;4 mile)
Please use L3 5DA for sat nav
Rail Liverpool Lime St Station is a 10 minute walk.
For local public transport please contact Merseytravel
Air Liverpool John Lennon Airport is 7 Miles away from the Foresight Centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day One: Data manipulation and Visualisation using the tidyverse</title>
      <link>/courses/advancingr-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/advancingr-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>PART I: Create a reproducible report using Markdown 1. What is R Markdown? R Markdown allows you to create documents that serve as a neat record of your analysis. In the world of reproducible research, we want other researchers to easily understand what we did in our analysis. You might choose to create an R markdown document as an appendix to a paper or project assignment that you are doing, upload it to an online repository such as Github, or simply to keep as a personal record so you can quickly look back at your code and see what you did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Two: Spatial data manipulation and visualisation in R</title>
      <link>/courses/advancingr-spatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/advancingr-spatial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>